Matthew Moyka

(C) (631) 988-6553 | mattmoyka@gmail.com | Long Island

Professional Summary

Driven software engineer leveraging a mechanical engineering degree and 2 years of account management in an engineering field. I love using problem solving to better myself and help others. I also bring experience managing 15+ client facing accounts in my previous role and hope to bring excellent engineering and quality to my next role.

Skills & Attributes

- Customer Account Managing/CRM
- Express, MongoDB
- Ruby, Rails
- Git Flow
- Heroku

- 6 months of Formal Sales Training
- Javascript, React
- Agile workflow
- HTML, CSS

Work History

General Assembly Fellow

08/2021 to 11/2021

- Build and maintain MERN and React on Rails applications
- Design and build applications with an agile development cycle, solo and on a team. Used github to keep track of and deploy all projects.
- Become fluent in a variety of frontend and backend languages and understand how they work as well as their similarities and differences.
- Learn complex computer science topics such as different sorting algorithms, hashing and binary search trees to name a few.

Trane Technologies – Account Manager

08/2018 to 08/2021

- Create business relationships with HVAC engineers and contractors to assist in the design, pricing, ordering and installation of Commercial HVAC equipment.
- Assist in implementing new data tracking software to save time during weekly meetings and eliminate the need to print 100s of sheets of paper a week.
- Successfully discovered customer pain points with past Trane account managers, remedied the issue and converted them back to buying our products.
- Responsible for learning a new product that was added to our line and educating my team about it's offerings and applications.

03/2017 to 01/2020

Long Island Awnings – Consultant

- Met with prospective clients to discuss the most effective way to implement a retractable awning on their home.
- Actively involved in the install process to better understand how to sell our product.
- Recorded and tracked installer's complaints in order to set better standards for customer expectation on install.
- Assisted the a new owner in implementing route planning software and an email automation system in order to increase closure rates.

Plaza Construction Corporation – Project Management Internship

06/2016 to 08/2016

Education

Bachelor of Science from University at Buffalo: Mechanical Engineering

Class of 2019

Certifications

• Trane Graduate Training Program Completion – (6 month formal sales engineering training)